An evil mutation embarks on a wave of brutal butchery.
Night of the Demon is a horror film directed by Jim West.
An anthropology professor and his students attempt to track down a Bigfoot responsible for
a rash of violent murders, only to uncover something even more sinister.
Professor Nugent, played by Michael Cutt.
Sheriff, played by Paul Kelleher.
Wanda, played by Melanie Graham.
Susan Nugent, played by Lynn Eastman-Rossi.
Dr. Paxton, played by Eugene Dow.
Dr. Harris, played by Don Hurst.
Night of the Demon is a 1980 American horror film directed by James C.
Wasson, written by Jim L.
Ball and Mike Williams, and starring Michael Cutt, Joy Allen, Robert Collings,
Jodi Lazarus, Richard Fields, Michael Lang, and Melanie Graham.
The film centers on an anthropologist who, along with a group of his pupils, embarks on an expedition to prove the existence of
Bigfoot in a rural region of Northern California, only to be stalked and systematically slaughtered by the creature.
Completed in 1979, the film was first released on
VHS in the United States in 1983.
Due to its graphic violence, the film was deemed a "video nasty" by the British Board of
Film Classification, and underwent heavy censorship in the United Kingdom.
It later received a DVD release from Code Red in
2011, sourced from a tape master.
In November 2021, Severin Films issued the film for the first time on Blu-ray, featuring a 2K
scan from the original film elements, which were previously alleged to be lost.
The film explores themes of chess, ritual, bigfoot, video nasty.
The tone is dark.